Damn it.
젠장.
Mr. Attorney.
미스터. 변호사.
Can you hear me, Mr. Attorney?
제 말 들리시나요, 변호사님?
Mr. Attorney!
미스터. 변호사!
Yes, what is it?
응, 그게 뭐야?
They're seriously shooting at me.
그들은 나에게 심각하게 총을 쏘고 있습니다.
They want me dead, or what?
그들은 내가 죽기를 원해요, 아니면 뭐?
Well, they're trying to restrict your liquidity, Sang-ung.
음, 그들은 제한을 시도하고 있어요 유동성 상웅씨.
But I've always been short on it.
하지만 나는 늘 부족했어요.
All right.
괜찮은.
Just hang in there a little longer.
조금만 더 참으세요.
Lure those thugs in and get to the branch manager's office.
깡패를 유인하세요 그리고 지점장 사무실로 가세요.
MANAGER'S OFFICE
관리자 사무실
That way leads...
그렇게 하면...
SECRET VAULT
비밀 금고
...straight to the secret vault.
...비밀 금고로 바로 이동
Once it's all set, I'll lower you down.
다 준비되면 내려드릴게요.
Damn it!
젠장!
Hey, Bun-mi. Hurry up!
안녕, 분미. 서둘러요!
Just try to hold on a little longer.
조금만 더 버티세요.
GIMHAE SAVINGS BANK
김해저축은행
Catch Kang Sang-ung first. We can't lose him.
강상웅을 먼저 잡아라. 우리는 그를 잃을 수 없습니다.
Yes, ma'am!
네, 부인!
Jeez. I might throw up.
이런. 토할 수도 있어요.
- I'm so full. - Hey.
- 배불러요. - 여기요.
What took you so long?
왜 그렇게 오래 걸렸나요?
What? I should've come later.
무엇? 나중에 왔어야 했는데.
Find Kang Sang-ung first.
먼저 강상웅을 찾아라.
They're here.
그들은 여기 있습니다.
Make the Mundane Vanguard and Jo Anna's crew fight.
평범한 선봉대 만들기 그리고 조안나의 선원들이 싸운다.
Then no one will be able to stop or come after us.
그렇다면 누구도 막을 수 없을 것이다 아니면 우리를 따라오세요.
We will be the only ones
우리는 유일한 사람이 될 것입니다
to enter the vault.
금고에 들어가려고.
We're heading to the manager's office now.
우리는 지금 관리실로 향하고 있습니다.
Don't come.
오지 마세요.
Mr. Attorney? Mr. Attorney!
변호사님? 변호사님!
Did we get cut off?
우리 잘렸나요?
Hurry, let's go.
서둘러, 가자.
We gotta hurry down.
서둘러야 해.
Mr. Attorney?
변호사님?
Mr. Attorney!
변호사님!
Mr. Attorney.
변호사님.
Mr. Attorney, are you okay?
변호사님, 괜찮으세요?
You always go beyond my expectations.
당신은 항상 내 기대 이상입니다.
Honestly, your superpower's the best as long as you have money.
솔직히 너의 초능력은 최고야 돈이 있는 한.
The problem is,
문제는,
you're low on cash now, right?
너 지금 현금이 부족해, 그렇지?
I have enough to shut you up.
나는 당신을 닥칠만큼 충분합니다.
A fun new product is coming out soon.
곧 재미있는 신제품이 출시될 예정입니다.
Hey.
여기요.
What do you even get out of all this?
이 모든 것에서 무엇을 얻나요?
Money, of course.
물론 돈입니다.
I need a lot of money to use your superpower properly.
돈이 많이 필요해요 초능력을 올바르게 사용하려면
REPLENISH YOUR CALORIES!
칼로리를 보충하세요!
Is that all?
그게 다야?
Totally disappointing.
정말 실망스럽습니다.
We might be out of our depth today.
오늘 우리는 우리의 깊이를 벗어났을 수도 있습니다.
No.
아니요.
Min-suk has something fun to tell me.
민석이가 나한테 재미있는 얘기를 해준다.
Gotta finish up and go.
마무리하고 가야겠네요.
Go this way!
이쪽으로 가세요!
You want a drink too?
너도 한잔 할래?
Mr. Attorney!
변호사님!
Mr. Attorney! Bun-mi!
변호사님! 분미!
Hey, can you hear me?
이봐, 내 말 들려?
Mr. Attorney!
변호사님!
A terrible stench.
지독한 악취.
I couldn't see it,
보이지 못했습니다.
but I could tell.
하지만 알 수 있었어요.
It's something strangely familiar
뭔가 이상할 정도로 친숙하다
yet ever-distant and nostalgic.
아직도 아득하고 향수를 불러일으키는
This awful smell is...
이 지독한 냄새는...
money.
돈.
What's so funny? We're about to die.
뭐가 그렇게 웃긴데? 우리는 곧 죽을 것입니다.
GIMHAE BANK UNDERGROUND VAULT
김해은행 지하 금고
What's behind that wall?
저 벽 뒤에는 무엇이 있나요?
The sewer line?
하수관?
It may stink just as bad, but it's something else.
악취도 나고 그럴 수도 있겠지만, 하지만 그것은 다른 것입니다.
Then what?
그러면 어쩌죠?
According to the floor plan,
평면도에 따르면,
this room measures 17 meters wide and 11 meters long.
이 방의 폭은 17미터입니다 그리고 길이는 11미터입니다.
But it can't possibly be that large.
그러나 그 규모가 그렇게 클 수는 없습니다.
This is reassuring.
이것은 안심이 됩니다.
Confidence really does come from money.
자신감은 실제로 돈에서 나옵니다.
Hi there.
안녕하세요.
Sang-ung.
상웅.
Mister.
아저씨.
I told you not to call me that.
내가 그렇게 부르지 말라고 했잖아.
So that's where the money was.
그래서 돈이 있던 곳이 바로 거기였습니다.
Your dad's piggy bank is on a whole other level.
너희 아빠의 돼지 저금통 완전히 다른 수준에 있습니다.
Bun-mi, take him with you and wait outside.
번미야, 데리고 가 그리고 밖에서 기다리세요.
I'm here to see this bastard today.
오늘은 그 놈을 만나러 왔습니다.
I gotta say goodbye before I go.
가기 전에 작별 인사를 해야 해요.
We'll head out first, then. Bun-mi, let's go.
그럼 우리 먼저 나가겠습니다. 분미야, 가자.
I always knew money was good,
나는 항상 돈이 좋다는 것을 알고 있었습니다.
but I didn't realize it was this good.
하지만 이것이 이렇게 좋은 줄은 몰랐습니다
You're in good shape.
당신은 좋은 상태입니다.
Money is good.
돈은 좋다.
You don't see anything in your way, huh?
가는 길에 아무것도 보이지 않죠?
No. I can see everything.
아니요. 모든 것이 보입니다.
Just take one hit.
한 번만 때리세요.
What?
무엇?
I have no idea what's going on.
무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 전혀 모르겠습니다.
Feels like I blacked out
정신을 잃은 것 같아요
after drinking last night.
어젯밤에 술을 마신 후
My superpowers aren't working.
초능력이 작동하지 않습니다.
What the hell?
대체 뭐야?
We're not going to arrest you. Don't worry.
우리는 당신을 체포하지 않을 것입니다. 괜찮아요.
Jeez.
이런.
- What is he doing? - Does that seem right?
- 그 사람 뭐하는 거예요? - 맞는 것 같나요?
Get out.
나가세요.
No superpowers, and no more of your nonsense.
초능력도 없고, 그리고 더 이상 말도 안되는 소리는 하지 마세요.
Excuse me?
실례합니다?
Just get out.
그냥 나가세요.
Hang on! Just wait.
잠깐만요! 기다리세요.
Jo Nathan.
조 네이선.
He's selling power-copying drugs.
그 사람은 복제약을 팔고 있어요.
- We'll check it. - No checking.
- 확인해 보겠습니다. - 확인하지 않습니다.
We gotta go get that bastard.
우리는 그 놈을 잡으러 가야 해요.
I told you.
내가 말했잖아.
More people are ending up in danger because of you.
점점 더 많은 사람들이 위험에 빠지고 있습니다 당신 때문에.
How is this on me?
나한테 이게 어때서?
You expect me to just sit
넌 내가 그냥 앉아 있기를 바라지?
and watch the world fall apart?
그리고 세상이 무너지는 걸 지켜볼까?
You think the world's only in danger now?
지금 세상이 위험에 처해 있다고 생각하시나요?
You may not know, but it was never safe. Not for a second.
당신은 모를 수도 있지만 결코 안전하지 않았습니다. 잠시도 아닙니다.
There have always been threats like the Mundane Vanguard and their drugs.
위협은 늘 있어왔지 Mundane Vanguard와 그들의 마약처럼 말이죠.
This fight started even before we were born,
이 싸움이 시작됐어 우리가 태어나기도 전에,
and it won't end even after we're dead.
그리고 우리가 죽어도 끝나지 않을 거예요.
Not all fights are head-on.
모든 싸움이 정면으로 벌어지는 것은 아닙니다.
You're not the only one in this fight.
이 싸움에서 당신은 유일한 사람이 아닙니다.
Get out.
나가세요.
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
I'm hungry. Let's hurry up and go.
배고파요. 서둘러서 가자.
GIMHAE SAVINGS BANK
김해저축은행
Take them back to the lab.
연구실로 다시 가져가세요.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
- Where's Lee Su-eun? - We haven't found her yet.
- 이수은은 어디 있지? - 아직 못 찾았어요.
Go get her now.
지금 가서 그녀를 데려오세요.
Whoa.
와.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Drop them.
버리세요.
Man.
남성.
So hot. Let's take these off.
너무 뜨거워요. 이것들을 떼어내자.
Thanks to my son-in-law, I finally got to see this place.
사위님 덕분에 드디어 이 곳을 보게 되었네요.
And who the hell are you?
그리고 당신은 도대체 누구입니까?
Are you Jo Won-do's daughter?
조원도 딸이냐?
You're just like your father.
당신은 당신의 아버지와 똑같습니다.
No, I'm not.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다.
Don't do anything stupid. Just stay right there.
어리석은 짓은 하지 마세요. 그냥 거기 있어.
I have no business with you.
나는 당신과 아무 상관이 없습니다.
You fought like crazy on someone else's money, passed out,
미친듯이 싸웠잖아 남의 돈으로 기절하고,
and ever since you came to,
그리고 당신이 여기 온 이후로,
your superpowers haven't worked?
당신의 초능력이 작동하지 않았나요?
Yes.
예.
You are maxed out.
당신은 최대치에 도달했습니다.
He's talking nonsense again.
그 사람 또 말도 안되는 소리를 하고 있군요.
What am I, a credit card?
나는 신용카드란 무엇인가?
- What? - Your superpowers are beyond your control.
- 뭐? - 당신의 초능력은 당신의 통제를 벗어났습니다.
Stay with me, okay?
나랑 같이 있어줘, 알았지?
That's why I told you from the start not to touch other people's money.
그래서 처음부터 말했잖아 남의 돈에 손대지 말라고.
I just thought you meant a general rule
난 그냥 일반적인 규칙을 뜻하는 줄 알았는데
about not touching other people's money.
남의 돈에 손대지 말라는 것.
Well, then...
그럼...
When will they come back?
그들은 언제 돌아올 것인가?
Who knows?
누가 알겠어요?
Like everything in life,
인생의 모든 것과 마찬가지로,
you shouldn't get too greedy.
너무 욕심을 부리면 안 됩니다.
Whether it's with money, food, or alcohol.
돈이든, 음식이든, 술이든 말이죠.
The moment you go beyond your limits, trouble starts.
한계를 넘어서는 순간, 문제가 시작됩니다.
So you mean
그러니까 말이에요
I never stood a chance from the start.
나는 처음부터 기회를 잡지 못했습니다.
If I fought with my own money while they were fucking strong,
내 돈으로 싸웠다면 그 사람들이 존나 강했던 동안,
this was never a fair game!
이것은 결코 공정한 게임이 아니었습니다!
If that was the plan, you could've made more money before giving me the powers!
그게 계획이었다면 넌 할 수 있었을 텐데 나에게 권한을 주기 전에 돈을 더 벌어라!
Sang-ung.
상웅.
- This isn't a fight about money. - It is about money.
- 돈 때문에 싸우는 게 아닙니다. - 돈에 관한 문제입니다.
You know that too. Don't be ridiculous!
당신도 그것을 알고 있습니다. 말도 안되는 소리하지 마세요!
What if you had no superpowers?
초능력이 없다면 어떨까요?
You wouldn't fight them?
그들과 싸우지 않을 건가요?
Now that you have no superpowers,
이제 당신에게는 초능력이 없습니다.
you're just gonna sit and watch them?
그냥 앉아서 지켜볼 건가요?
Hardly anyone would spend 30 million won from their mom
돈을 쓰는 사람은 거의 없을 것이다 엄마한테 3000만원
to save complete strangers.
완전히 낯선 사람을 구하기 위해.
It wasn't the superpower that saved those people.
초능력이 아니었어 그게 그 사람들을 구한 거야.
It was you.
당신이었습니다.
Have a good think about it.
잘 생각해 보세요.
Our strength
우리의 힘
doesn't come from money.
돈에서 나오는 게 아니다.
While fighting...
싸우면서...
while protecting something...
무언가를 보호하면서...
there comes a moment when you realize
깨닫는 순간이 옵니다
that money doesn't really matter.
그 돈은 별로 중요하지 않아요.
You need to realize that before you can use your superpower again.
당신은 그것을 깨달아야합니다 초능력을 다시 사용하기 전에.
THE MUNDANE VANGUARD
평범한 선봉대
Damn it.
젠장.
You don't have what it takes to contain his superpower.
당신은 필요한 것이 없습니다 그의 초능력을 억제하기 위해.
Living like a moron is probably worse for you than death.
바보처럼 살아요 아마도 당신에게는 죽음보다 더 나쁠 것입니다.
That's how pride works.
그것이 바로 자존심이 작동하는 방식입니다.
Once you let it go, there's nothing left.
일단 놓으면 아무것도 남지 않습니다.
Chairman Jo.
조 회장.
JO ANNA
조안나
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
No matter how hard you try,
아무리 노력해도
some things can't be separated from a person.
어떤 것들은 분리될 수 없습니다 사람에게서.
BORROWER: JO SHIN-IL LENDER: PARK HYEONG-DO
차용자 : 조신일 대출기관: 박형도
The truth and my money.
진실과 내 돈.
No money in this world belongs to you.
이 세상에 돈은 당신의 것이 아닙니다.
It says so right here in the ledger.
여기 장부에 그렇게 적혀 있어요.
It took me a long time to recover what you hid.
시간이 오래 걸렸어요 숨겨둔 것을 되찾기 위해.
It takes a hundred years to build...
만드는데 백년이 걸려요..
but it all comes crashing down in a day.
하지만 하루아침에 다 무너져 버립니다.
I'm not as forgiving as my father.
나는 아버지만큼 용서하지 않습니다.
Take care of yourself until you pay all my money back.
자신을 돌봐 네가 내 돈 다 갚을 때까지.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You're going to regret this.
당신은 이것을 후회하게 될 것입니다.
The real regret is what you're doing right now.
진짜 후회 지금 당신이 하고 있는 일이 바로 그것이다.
I'll keep this money safe for the time being.
이 돈은 내가 안전하게 보관할게 당분간.
Take it all.
다 가져가세요.
- Yes, ma'am!
- 네, 부인!
Screw superpowers.
나사 초능력.
Losing them after having them is even more exhausting,
갖고 난 후 잃어버린 경우 더욱 지친다
both physically and mentally.
육체적으로나 정신적으로
Min-suk?
민석이?
Hey, Min-suk!
야, 민석아!
Hey, Min...
안녕, 민...
Min-suk!
민석아!
Damn it.
젠장.
- Hello-- - I was really moved by what you said.
- 안녕하세요-- - 말씀하신 내용에 정말 감동받았습니다.
Where is Min-suk?
민석이는 어디 있어요?
Sang-ung, I'm fine.
상웅 씨, 저는 괜찮아요.
So don't worry too much.
그러니 너무 걱정하지 마세요.
Min-suk.
민석아.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Hang in there. I'll be there soon.
조금만 참으세요. 곧 갈게요.
Just a little...
조금...
Why are you making things complicated?
왜 일을 복잡하게 만드나요?
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
It's always been you.
항상 당신이었습니다.
Fine. Then I'll come to you.
괜찮은. 그럼 내가 당신에게 갈게요.
I'll be there, so let Min-suk...
내가 갈 테니까 민석이를...
Hey!
이봐!
You fucking bastard!
이 빌어먹을 놈!
I said I'd come! I'm coming!
나는 올 것이라고 말했다! 내가 간다!
That's for me to decide.
그건 내가 결정하는 거야.
You just wait quietly.
조용히 기다리시면 됩니다.
Fuck.
젠장.
The person you called is unavailable.
전화하신 분은 부재중입니다.
You think you're gonna win, don't you?
당신은 당신이 이길 것이라고 생각하지 않습니까?
You'll never be able to beat Kang Sang-ung.
넌 절대 못할 거야 강상웅을 이기기 위해.
Why do you think that?
왜 그렇게 생각하세요?
Sang-ung...
상웅...
He's not good at calculations.
그 사람은 계산을 잘 못해요.
So he always ends up doing everything he thinks is right.
그래서 그는 항상 결국엔 그가 생각하는 모든 것이 옳습니다.
Even if it's impossible.
불가능하더라도.
Even if the odds are against him.
그에게 불리한 상황이라 할지라도.
I see.
알겠어요.
That's why that bastard is so broke.
그래서 그 놈이 그렇게 망가진 거야.
No. He never had any money to begin with.
아니요. 그는 처음부터 돈이 없었습니다.
How could you possibly live with someone who spends his own money helping others?
어떻게 누군가와 함께 살 수 있니? 누가 자신의 돈을 다른 사람을 돕는 데 쓰나요?
Hey, you've got it backward.
이봐요, 거꾸로 말씀하셨군요.
He puts up with someone like me because he's a pushover.
그 사람은 나 같은 사람도 참아준다 왜냐면 그 사람은 만만찮은 사람이거든요.
But I want him to be a pushover only for me.
하지만 난 그 사람이 만만찮은 사람이었으면 좋겠어 나에게만.
How touching.
정말 감동적이네요.
Of course. We just got married.
물론. 우리는 방금 결혼했어요.
Right now, it feels like you've stolen my husband.
지금은 그런 느낌이에요 당신은 내 남편을 훔쳤어요.
Our family meeting got ruined because of you.
우리 가족 모임이 망가졌어 당신 때문에.
We haven't even had our wedding!
우리는 결혼식도 치르지 않았어요!
You're going to lose.
당신은 잃을 것입니다.
Just wait and see.
그냥 기다려 보세요.
We'll find out who is right.
우리는 누가 옳은지 알아낼 것입니다.
Nobody move!
아무도 움직이지 마세요!
Jo Nathan is selling power-copying drugs.
Jo Nathan은 복제약을 판매하고 있습니다.
We'll check it.
확인해 보겠습니다.
No checking. We gotta go get that bastard.
확인하지 않습니다. 우리는 그 놈을 잡으러 가야 해요.
You didn't arrest anyone. Why did you even go to Gimhae?
당신은 누구도 체포하지 않았습니다. 김해에는 왜 갔나요?
What's going on right now?
지금 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Kang Sang-ung. Why did you let him go?
강상웅. 왜 그를 놓아줬나요?
Because he did nothing wrong.
왜냐하면 그는 아무 잘못도 하지 않았기 때문입니다.
He broke into a vault, and he's innocent? Are you serious?
그 사람이 금고에 침입했는데, 무죄인가요? 진심인가요?
Listen up, you guys.
잘 들어라, 너희들.
There's one thing in the world that's worth more than money.
세상에는 한가지가 있다 그것은 돈보다 더 가치 있는 일이다.
Guess what it is.
그것이 무엇인지 맞춰보세요.
What?
무엇?
It's time.
시간이다.
That's why we're always short on time.
그래서 우리는 항상 시간이 부족해요.
You look great.
당신은 멋져 보인다.
Don't be late next time.
다음에는 늦지 마세요.
Where is Min-suk?
민석이는 어디 있어요?
Before we get to that, I need to test something on you.
그 이야기를 하기 전에, 당신에게 뭔가 테스트를 해볼 필요가 있어요.
What kind of test?
어떤 종류의 테스트인가요?
You collapsed in the vault.
당신은 금고에서 쓰러졌습니다.
If you're damaged goods,
상품이 파손된 경우,
there's no need to waste our time.
시간을 낭비할 필요는 없어요.
That's when I realized.
그때 깨달았습니다.
If I don't have my superpowers,
나에게 초능력이 없다면
I'm completely useless to them.
나는 그들에게 전혀 쓸모가 없습니다.
If you beat me,
당신이 나를 이길 경우,
I'll take you to her.
내가 당신을 그녀에게 데려갈게요.
If you lose...
패배하면...
you and that bitch
너랑 그년
will both end up dead.
둘 다 결국 죽게 될 거야.
I'm sorry to say this,
이런 말을 해서 미안해요.
but I need to hear a fun story from Min-suk.
하지만 재미있는 이야기를 들어야 해 민석에게서.
I can't die right now.
지금은 죽을 수 없어요.
Min-suk.
민석아.
Where is she?
그녀는 어디에 있나요?
What's wrong? You said you could see everything.
무슨 일이야? 모든 것을 볼 수 있다고 하셨습니다.
Where is Min-suk?
민석이는 어디 있어요?
Where is Min-suk? Damn it!
민석이는 어디 있어요? 젠장!
You really can't use it anymore?
정말 더 이상 사용할 수 없나요?
I should dispose of both of you.
너희 둘 다 처리해야겠어.
I have no business with you.
나는 당신과 아무 상관이 없습니다.
So just tell me.
그러니 그냥 말해 보세요.
Min-suk.
민석아.
Where is she?
그녀는 어디에 있나요?
Die and meet her.
죽어서 그녀를 만나세요.
Don't move, or you'll get holes in your body.
움직이지 마세요. 아니면 몸에 구멍이 날 것입니다.
DIVORCE ATTORNEY BYEON HO-IN
이혼전문변호사 변호인
BEOMHA LOGISTICS
범하로지스틱스
It's here.
여기 있어요.
FIRST FLOOR
1층
The Mundane Vanguard thugs are guarding every entrance.
평범한 Vanguard 폭력배 모든 입구를 지키고 있습니다.
HORIZONTAL CROSS SECTION
수평 횡단면
The same would go for Min-suk.
민석씨도 마찬가지입니다.
It's suicide to go in now.
지금 들어가는 것은 자살 행위입니다.
We're all gonna die. Min-suk, and the rest of us too!
우리는 모두 죽을거야. 민석이도 그렇고 우리 모두도요!
Even with powers, it won't be easy.
능력이 있어도 쉽지 않을 것이다.
When we first met,
우리 처음 만났을 때,
you asked why I helped them, right?
내가 왜 그들을 도왔는지 물었지?
The people who were in the bus accident.
버스사고를 당한 사람들.
I did it because I had to. Do I need a reason?
해야 했기 때문에 그렇게 했습니다. 이유가 필요합니까?
I would've done it without superpowers.
초능력이 없었다면 해냈을 거예요.
One way or another.
어떤 식 으로든.
Willpower alone isn't enough.
의지력만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
In this situation, nothing's adding up!
이 상황에서는 아무것도 추가되지 않습니다!
I'm bad at things like calculations.
나는 계산 같은 것을 잘 못한다.
BEOMHA LOGISTICS
범하로지스틱스
Now I kind of understand what Dad meant.
이제 아버지께서 무슨 말씀을 하신지 어느 정도 이해가 되었습니다.
My strength does not come from money.
나의 힘은 돈에서 나오지 않습니다.
My strength comes out
힘이 나네요
to protect something more important than money.
무언가를 보호하기 위해 돈보다 더 중요합니다.
Min-suk,
민석님,
I won't be late this time.
이번에는 늦지 않을 거예요.
Subtitle translation by Yun-hee Jang
장윤희 자막 번역